Guide to the John Hicks Papers, 1950-2015 RL.00537
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audio and Moving Image Materials, 1975-2006 and undated, 5 boxes
  - Audio Cassettes
    - Café de Copains John Hicks Solo Piano 6/86 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-013)
    - John/Ray (Elise) Bearwest 8/4/87 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-014)
    - JH West End Café 9/25/87 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-015)
    - John Hicks Quintet 1-9-88 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-016)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Café Decopains 4/28/88 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-017)
    - Barron/Hicks Quartet Sept 3, 1989 from Candid CD 79044 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-018)
    - John Hicks/Mickey Bass 7/24/90 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-019)
    - John Hicks/David Young at Café des Copains; Oct 18, 1990 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-020)
    - McShann/Hicks Reservoir 9/14/92 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-021)
    - John Hicks at Session House 3-13-92 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-022)
    - John Hicks/Idris Muhammad/Ray Drummond Bradley's and Birdland 12/26/92 12/29/92 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-023)
    - McShann/Hicks Reservoir 11/11/92 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-024)
    - John Hicks 12/26/92 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-025)
    - NY Unit - John Hicks, Richard Davis, Tatsuya Nakamura 2/23/93 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-026)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Live at the BlueNote 6/28/93 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-027)
    - Walter Bishop/John Hicks/Phil Boler/Alen Dobson Hartford Jazz Fest 7/26/93 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-028)
    - John Hicks Sextet 7/27/93 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-029)
    - Walter Bishop/John Hicks Live in Torino Italy 9-8-93 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-030)
    - Birdland 10/29/93 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-031)
    - John Hicks/David Williams Bradley's 6/29/94 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-032)
    - John Hicks/Roy Hargrove Bradley's 8/94 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-033)
    - John Hicks DAT 1 11/13/94 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-034)
    - John Hicks DAT 2 11/13/94 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-035)
    - John Hicks #1 8-8-95 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-036)
    - John Hicks #2 8-8-95 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-037)
    - The Five Spot 9/30/95 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-038)
    - John Hicks Excerpts 11-29-95 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-039)
    - J.H. WKCR 1 of 2 4/11/96 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-040)
    - J.H. WKCR 2 of 2 4/11/96 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-041)
    - John Hicks Trio +1 8/24-25/96 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-042)
    - John Hicks and Elise Wood, Pensacola 4/20/97 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-043)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood WUNF Session 4/18/97 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-044)
    - John Hicks and Elise Wood, Pensacola 4/17/97 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-045)
    - Birdland 4/98 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-046)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood 4-25-98 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-047)
    - John Hicks Trio 7-18-99 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-048)
    - John Hicks/Arlene Smith Oct 14, 99 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-049)
    - Hicks/Carter/Davis/Nakamura/Wood Ichikawa Grand Hotel Nov 13, 99 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-050)
    - Spirit of Life at Sweet Basil 12/21/99 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-051)
    - Spirit of Life at Sweet Basil 12/21/99 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-052)
    - Jazz Tribe, Hicks Time March 17, 2000 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-053)
    - Blues Alley 6/9/01 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-054)
    - Manhattan Burn Birdland 8/01 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-055)
    - Jazz From Studio 4 John Hicks 2 12/11/01 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-056)
    - Jazz From Studio 4 John Hicks 1 12/11/01 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-057)
    - Jazz From Studio 4 John Hicks 3 12/11/01 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-058)
    - John Hicks/Joe Locke Jazz at the Penthouse 3/15/02 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-059)
    - John Hicks/Joe Locke Jazz at the Penthouse 3/16/02 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-060)
    - John Hicks All-Star Quintet (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-061)
    - John Hicks All-Star Quintet (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-062)
    - John Hicks at Zanzibar Blue 2 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-063)
    - JH Qtet w/ Bobby Hutcherson 4 Queens Vegas (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-064)
    - John Hicks 2 B'Land (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-065)
    - [untitled] (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-066)
    - John Hicks Quintet Visiones 3/8 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-067)
    - John Hicks 1st Set (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-068)
    - Blues Alley 2 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-069)
    - Blues Alley 1 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-070)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Themes 1/5 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-071)
    - JH St. Mark's Church (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-072)
    - John Hicks Sextet Visiones (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-073)
    - John Hicks Quintet (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-074)
    - John Hicks Trio/Sextet (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-075)
    - Visiones Sextet 3/9 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-076)
    - John Hicks 5, Jazz Showcase (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-077)
    - Cynthia Scott/John Hicks Trio (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-078)
    - John Hicks Big Band (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-079)
    - John Hicks, Jazz at Lincoln Center (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-080)
    - John Hicks Quintet/Sextet (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-081)
    - JH Big Band, Smalls Paradise (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-082)
    - John Hicks, Elise Wood, Walter Booker; Urban Moods (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-083)
    - John Hicks, Elise Wood, Clifford Jordan, Walter Booker, Jimmy Cobb (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-084)
    - The Reunion Legacy Band, The Legacy, EBC-102 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-085)
    - John Hicks, In Concert, Theresa Records, TR-123 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-086)
    - John Hicks, In Concert, Theresa Records, TR-123 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-087)
    - Hicks/Wood, Urban Moods (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-088)
    - Hicks/Wood Inc. (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-089)
    - John Hicks Solo Proposal #1 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-090)
    - JH, Aaron Davis Hall (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-091)
    - Osaka - Rehearsal 1 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-092)
    - Hicks (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-093)
    - Charles Mingus Retrospective 1, WKCR (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-094)
    - Mindwine, Jupiter (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-095)
    - JH #1 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-096)
    - John Hicks, Sacramento (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-097)
    - Jazz Club au due des Lombards, 05-04-90 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-098)
    - John Hicks, Songs of Survival (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-099)
    - Michael Gauthier/John Hicks, 1 of 2 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-100)
    - JH/EW Messina (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-101)
    - Elise Wood/John Hicks (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-102)
    - John Hicks Brass and Reed Ensemble (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-103)
    - [untitled] (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-104)
    - Hicks, Passin' Thru (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-105)
    - Rehearsal, with piano (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-106)
    - John Hicks, record date (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-107)
    - JH/EW w/ Spirit of Life (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-108)
    - JH/EW w/ Spirit of Life (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-109)
    - Hicks orig. (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-110)
    - J.H. Super Mix (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-111)
    - (A) Randy Weston/ (B) John Hicks (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-112)
    - JH/EW Strings (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-113)
    - John Hicks, Expectations (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-114)
    - John Hicks His Story (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-115)
    - Monmouth Co. Library Concert 1/25/85 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-116)
    - Jazz Alley 10/20/88 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-117)
    - John Hicks 4/3/2003 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-118)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Incorporated, Courtesy of Theresa Records (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-119)
    - Elise Wood, Jazz Flute, MAC 8-16-83 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-120)
    - Sonny Rollins' Selections, John's Copy (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-121)
    - Betty Carter, Jazz Profile (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-122)
    - Goodie Mob (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-123)
    - [untitled] (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-124)
    - [untitled] (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-125)
    - Yosemite Park 7/14/94 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-126)
    - Reel #2 Trio 2-19-97 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-127)
    - Elise Wood B'Land (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-128)
    - New Voice of Chamber Jazz (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-129)
    - Harlem Diary (in sequence) 3-19-96 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-130)
    - Symphony in Blue (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-131)
    - Mind Wine (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-132)
    - 72nd Street Bandshell 10/3/80 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-133)
    - Elise Wood Trio "Live" Tape One (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-134)
    - Hicks/Wood Hi Speed Copy 11/20/84 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-135)
    - John Hicks at Café de Copains Toronto April 20, 1988 Tape 1 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-136)
    - Hartford, Hicks Inc (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-137)
    - Jazz Showcase 10/22/88 JHAS5 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-138)
    - Tape 1, West End, 9/27/87 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-139)
    - Jazz Showcase 10/20/88 2nd Set JHAS5 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-140)
    - John Hicks and Garnet Brown, March 10, 1991 #1 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-141)
    - Urban Moods, Boogie Woogie Studios (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-143)
    - St. Peter's Church, 4/8/79 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-143)
    - Pori Jazz 7/14 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-144)
    - NY Unit Trio w/ Elise Wood (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-145)
    - Low G Shore (con't) (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-146)
    - 3rd Set w/ Curtis, full house, 5/5 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-147)
    - EW St. Peter's (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-148)
    - EW w/ Bishop, 4/22 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-149)
    - Spirit of Life, 8/18/99 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-150)
    - John Hicks, Jazzmobile, 8/1/85 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-151)
    - Tape 2, 2nd Set, West End, 9/25/87 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-152)
    - Reel #1 Trio 2-19-97 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-153)
    - Roland Hanna Trio, New Voice, 4/8/88 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-154)
    - Wine Spot 1st Set 2/26 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-155)
    - March 93, Early St. Louise, J and E (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-156)
    - Sweet Basil w/ John Hicks All Stars, 11/1/84 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-157)
    - Chico, Arthur, w/ John Hicks, Ronnie Scotts (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-158)
    - Spirit of Life w/ Ted Carson (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-159)
    - Blues Alley (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-160)
    - John Hicks 2nd Set (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-161)
    - Lenox Lounge, 6/30/00 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-162)
    - Spirit of Life, 3/8/99 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-163)
    - John Hicks Quintet, 12/29/96 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-164)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Inc, 1st Pres Church, 3/9/86 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-165)
    - John Hicks and Co, 1-7-97 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-166)
    - Luminous (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-167)
    - Blues Alley, 1993 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-168)
    - Sweet Basil, 1/30/98 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-169)
    - New York Unit Piano Trio at Colton vol. 1 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-170)
    - New Dawn, Elise Wood (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-171)
    - Café Jupiter, 7/86 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-172)
    - Elise Wood, flute (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-173)
    - John Hicks on WCWP w/ March Greene, part 2, 3-26-1999 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-174)
    - Lenox Lounge, 3rd set, 6/30 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-175)
    - Five Spot, 12/6/95 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-176)
    - 2nd Set, Bistro (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-177)
    - John Hicks "Steadfast" Strata East (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-178)
    - JH/Joann - Betty, Bradley's (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-179)
    - John Hicks All-Star Quintet, 10-9-88 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-180)
    - John Hicks Quintet, 1988 St. Louis Jazz Festival (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-181)
    - Leitch-Hicks, Duality, Reservoir 134 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-182)
    - John Hicks Quintet, 10-8-89 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-183)
    - John Hicks, 5-11-94 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-184)
    - Arthur's - JH/EW (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-185)
    - Zinc Bar, EW, 6/21 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-186)
    - Ojos de Rojo (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-187)
    - JH/EW, 4/23, 4/24 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-188)
    - Zinno's, JH/EW, 4/23 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-189)
    - Reh, St. Mark's (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-190)
    - Luminous (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-191)
    - Elise Wood, Jazz Flute, MAC 8-16-83 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-192)
    - Café Decopains 5/88 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-193)
    - Hicks/Wood WNYC, 8-18-95 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-194)
    - Hicks/Pharoah (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-195)
    - Jazz Showcase, JHAS5 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-196)
    - Live Sweet Basil (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-197)
    - Bistro, 1st Set (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-198)
    - Elise Wood, 7/31/85 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-199)
    - Peter Leitch Quartet, Mean What You Say (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-200)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, Proposal 2, 12/19/96 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-201)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Incorporated (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-202)
    - John Hicks Trio +1 8/24-25/96, no. 1 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-203)
    - John Hicks 2 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-204)
    - Klom, JHAS5, 1st Set (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-205)
    - John Hicks and Garnet Brown, March 10, 1991 #2 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-206)
    - John Hicks and Elise Wood, La Jolla, 10-9-89 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-207)
    - John Hicks, Zanzibar Blue, 1 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-208)
    - Remy's New Year's Eve, 12/31/85 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-209)
    - Piece for my Peace (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-210)
    - New York Unit Piano Trio at Colton vol. 2 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-211)
    - The Keystone Trio, 12/4/95 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-212)
    - JH #2 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-213)
    - John Hicks Trio +1 8/24-25/96, no. 2 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-214)
    - Nilva Record Date, Nov 88 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-215)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, At Murray's 1/2 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-216)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, 3-12-91 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-217)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, 3-12-91 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-218)
    - Hicks Inc, Hartford 1989 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-219)
    - New York Unit Piano Trio at Colton (no cut) (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-220)
    - Billy R and John in Guelph - I (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-221)
    - Sherman Irby - song tape (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-222)
    - Lenox Lounge, 1st Set, 7/1 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-223)
    - Chico and Arthur w/ John Hicks, Ronnie Scott's (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-224)
    - Small's 2/8-9/85 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-225)
    - Pori Jazz Fest Kansas, 7/17/99 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-226)
    - Visiones Quintet 3/10 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-227)
    - John Hicks and Co, 1/6-7/97 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-228)
    - A. Hicks Proposal 2 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-229)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, At Murray's 2/2 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-230)
    - Reh 1/30/88 (Box 29, Item 2011-0007-231)
    - Miscellaneous Audio Cassettes (Box 30)
      Ca. 200 audio cassettes from the personal collection of John Hicks. Consists primarily of commercially available recordings of various jazz musicians.
  - Other Audio Materials
    Contains one LP and twenty-seven CDs. Original titles retained.
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, Inc. Luminous (Nilva Records, NQ 3418) (1 LP) (Box 31)
    - Hicks-Wood Sextet, Birdland, April 2004 (2 CDs) (Box 31)
    - Hicks-Wood Sextet, Birdland, April 2003 (7 CDs) (Box 31)
    - Wood and Hicks 2 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Hicks, Wood, 2-20-01 (4 CDs) (Box 31)
    - Hicks/Wood, Lebanon, August 2004 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, Live In Paris Hiwood Records, Inc CD 4621-1 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Woody Herman and His Orchestra, Live In Seattle Moon Records MCD 0002-2 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Betty Carter, Live at the Bottom Line, Sept 5, 1975 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - John Hicks Big Band at Aaron Davis Hall (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Hicks #1 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Hicks #2 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Hicks, Hayes, Williams (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Frank Morgan, John Hicks, Bakery (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - John Hicks Plays the Music of Earl Fatha Hines, 6/26/03 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - John Hicks Interview, XM 70 Real Jazz (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - XM Radio, 5/3/03 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Standards in Jazz, Tribute to John Hicks, 6-8-06 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - Peter Leitch Quartet, California Concert, 5/1/99 (1 CD) (Box 31)
    - John Hicks, Some Other Time, 1981; 2 audiovisual items 2 copies (Box 36)
    - John Hicks in Concert, 1986; 2 audiovisual items 2 copies (Box 36)
    - John Hicks, 1984; 1 audiovisual items (Box 36)
    - The Time, 1981; 1 audiovisual items (Box 36)
    - The Hoppin' John Orchestra, Reunion Days, 2014; 1 audiovisual items (Box 36)
  - Moving Image Materials
    Contains one DVD, one Betamax, and seventeen VHS items. Original titles retained.
    - John Hicks Memorial (DVD) (Box 31)
    - John Hicks 6/8/86 (Betamax) (Box 31)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Sextet, Birdland, 4/27/02 (VHS) (Box 31)
    - Live at B'Land Q'Tet (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks, "Homecoming" and "Motivation" (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks, Jazz Appreciation Class at Visiones, 10/25/94 (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks Ensemble Plays Billy Strayhorn at Aaron Davis Hall, 12/6/2003 (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, Paris (VHS) (Box 32)
    - Elise Wood/John Hicks, Wedding Party (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, Vermont Jazz Center, 10/16/93 (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood, At Lenox Lounge (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks Octet, Jazzmobile in Harlem, 7/8/02 (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks, Jazzmobile in Harlem, 7/21/03 (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks, Duke Jazz Ensemble, 2/25/2000 (VHS) (Box 32)
    - Pori Jazz Novo Stage, 7/16/99 (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks, Demo/Interview at Murry's (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Sextet, Birdland, 4/23/98 (VHS) (Box 32)
    - John Hicks/Elise Wood Quartet at Cecil's, 6/23/05 (VHS) (Box 32)